PATRICK WONG

patrick.wong@uwaterloo.ca https://patwong.github.io/ **US Citizen**

Cell: (226) 868-1798 US: (408) 800-5762

Home: (905) 812-2880

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Mathematics, University of Waterloo

October 2016

Computer Science and Computational Mathematics Major, Combinatorics and Optimization Minor

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Technical Skills

Languages (Proficient) MATLAB, Python, C#, SQL, (Experienced) C++/C, Java, Ruby, Hadoop, Spark

Frameworks/Tools Rails, Git, Linux, PostgreSQL

Relevant Personal Projects

Rails Tutorial App February 2017 – Present

- Mini-microblog service with authenticated user signup and login, deployed on Heroku

MLB Batted Ball Stat Visualizations

December 2016 - Present

Visualizing MLB hitters' stats with interactive graphs using Python

notedump November 2016 – December 2016

Windows desktop application with a tabbed interface, to organize text files

<u>CS 350 OS/161</u> May 2014 – August 2014

- Implemented synchronization primitives, system calls, and a virtual memory system for the OS/161 kernel

Relevant Coursework

CS 476 – Numeric Computation for Financial Modeling
CS 475 – Computational Linear Algebra
CS 473 – Medical Image Processing
CS 466 – Algorithm Design and Analysis

CS 458 – Computer Security and Privacy CS 436 – Networks and Distributed Computer Systems

CS 350 – Operating Systems CS 341 – Algorithms

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Intern, Loring Ward, San Jose, California

May 2013 – August 2013

- Installed physical workstations and prepared fresh computer image for new users
- Fixed and maintained desktop/laptop hardware and issued requests for new equipment
- Resolved user problems with Windows 7, Outlook, and internet browsers

Assistant, Gold Gold Travel, Mississauga, Ontario

May 2012 – August 2012

- Searched and booked flights for clients
- Phoned tour agencies to confirm bookings and sent travel information to travel agents
- Received phone calls from clients and resolved their queries